I don't know the order of the May of the Minority,
Minority City Council,
Regards, Kevin Means,
Minority City Council.
From Monday, February 5, 2021,
to Bo Gampon,
A Schedule of Personal Parents,
We have none.
Three Claims.
Close to a group.
Second.
Second. Second.
Second. Second. Second.
Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second. Second
And there's just been a recent change of board members.
Three members, their terms were fulfilled and needed to be replaced.
So we've got three new board members, new president and vice president.
And we're currently working on getting everything organized, trying to figure out what was going right, what was going wrong.
So everything has something going wrong along the way.
Hopefully this will make a big difference.
Last year, we served approximately 4,000 citizens.
Now that's not members.
That citizens, we have what they call docs there.
We have meals.
They serve them there.
They can pick them up there to take home.
And docs will deliver food to the people.
We serve a senior with, we play games.
We have bingo, we have bingo for fundraisers.
But we play dominoes, cards, we've got three pool tables.
And you know, small library.
We have a fitness, small fitness center with a couple of treadmills and stuff like that.
Bicycles, stuff like that.
We got physical fitness in there for DVDs.
We can go into room and set and just exercise basically as what it is.
Various clubs, use our meeting rooms.
Local funding is integral to the center.
The people that provide it are grand, gateway, united way, city of Miami.
They help us quite a bit.
In Taylor's hospital.
Recently, we have partnered, I guess you'd call it, with Chief Harper.
of the Peoria tribe, they've showed interest in helping us out at the Senior Center by replacing
lights, painting, updating our chairs, giving us better chairs and stuff, our chairs are
pretty bad in some spots and keeping the grounds clean, they've already done some work on
that.
They've pledged $10,000 to do all that work.
One of the major things that they're looking at doing is our door for the handicapped, the
automatic door opener, hasn't worked for quite a while.
We just don't have money to fix it, but that is one of their top agendas for the way I understand.
The Ottawa County election board, they use the building for their polling, be to tax
service, which they're going on right now, they're doing taxes for the seniors and stuff,
which is quite a big health, really.
Let's see here, says here, the Companions has, Ottawa County Senior Companions has an office
there that helps our senior people in town that needs help at home and that's, that's about
all I have.
I would like to add, already equipment that I talked about, the crowd meals, the pool tables,
the bicycle, the stuff for the exercise, it's in pretty poor condition and we're currently
trying to find ways to earn money to fix it up, so I just want to let you know that.
We would like, if you could, find time to come out and visit us and let us show you around and
show you what it's like out there, what we do, though, is there have any questions or anything?
So, Sam, I think it was last year, two years, around the two years ago.
We actually took an opportunity to have one of our work study sessions at your facility, so
the council was able to go out there and spend some time there, we had our meeting and then
got a tour of everything in the ground, so it was really good.
I appreciate that.
I think out of that was the deal that burnt off, that's who fixed the fencing out there.
I think there were a lot of things that I think should be fencing, I believe.
I think that fixed the fencing concept, she far further get involved, I think, because he talked
to his phone on about.
He was certain, yeah, he called was very appreciative to see that as well, so he's really
taken an entry.
We wasn't, we wasn't aware of that.
Sam was a Doc program, was that, was that a free meal for the seniors?
He's a reduced rate.
He's part of it, on the meals, the daily meals.
I understand it's the same price for seniors or anybody.
They will deliver to the home, I believe, for $5, they can come in and at the center and eat it or take it home for $3.50.
Yeah, that's nice.
It's not a bad price for a meal.
Yeah.
Thank you so much for that information.
Don't question us at home.
I will.
Thank you.
Same price.
Number six, letter engagement with the land plan, consultant incorporated to prepare a conceptual master plan for a new sports complex.
I fixed $25,000.
Give it.
Yes.
You guys remember back in the spring of last year at 2023.
You guys kind of gave me a little direction to put together a plan in a special plan.
What a sports conference.
My little plaque.
My little bone.
So in July I asked for the funding to get that plan.
To get that plan to start it.
And basically what this this plan is with land plan is to start that.
Start to conceptual design.
But what one will look like roughly a cost.
I'm the acreage of the things like that.
So this is just the first step of that.
And if you guys approve this.
We will start setting up meetings with land plan to start put together.
Hey, truck.
This is something that the ad foundation has been trying to do for quite some years.
And they've already drawn up plans like this.
And if I'm not mistaken, they came to the city the time or two.
The what broke hoop.
Leave that athletic.
Oh, and where the agent?
Yeah.
I don't know.
They have all this stuff thrown up already.
I've seen a few things.
Because I was first involved in soccer fields, baseball fields, basketball courts,
indoor outdoor rodeo grounds, monster truck and rena.
Right.
I mean, all of that stuff.
What it looks like.
What it would cost.
How many acreage.
How much acreage and stuff they would need.
To me, it would make sense to get with them.
And look at their stuff.
First before.
The city goes out and spends up to $25,000.
I have something drawn up.
That's already drawn up.
That the city could utilize.
At least look at and see what their stuff is before.
Even thinking about moving forward with this.
You know, is there 100 acres within the city.
My Emma that this could even be.
I don't know.
I said, I just kind of went off.
What was.
Right.
But I have no problems.
I don't find them.
I assume with that part.
We're getting on our bucks and I've seen some pieces of it, and the past the Nick Burst
started that program.
I was actually on that board and then it just kind of fizzled out and hurt a bunch
from them.
I mean, I'll talk about it on a weekly basis, but other things, so I have a problem seeing
what he has available to see people help us and what we're just looking at, you know.
I think it's just a design.
Yeah.
Over there, it's not been approved.
Just to see where it looks like.
The funding for this to get started in the plans, it's already been approved, are you guys
in July?
Well, maybe in the light of already having that information, do we want to table that?
And then, until you talk of the M&C, see if they have an M&C, they have an M&C, they have an
M&C in the middle of the morning.
If you probably applied that $25,000 to something else, maybe, all right, I actually, I've been
a prop set now, and to see what he's got, and see if people on the chair were just, I mean,
I think he would probably be willing to share.
I mean, I know that's the ultimate goal of them is to have a sports complex within a setting
line.
So, if this does exist, could we have a work study, this would be a topic in a work study
session where he could kind of present what was already out there?
So, we can see it.
Great.
I've got problems out of all here.
What I'm just trying to see, I mean, if we can save $25,000, I'm not spending, if something's
already been drawn out of some of these.
I've seen bits and pieces of it, not in full scale, what I've looked like from where he's got
on his dad.
There was to see what he's got.
Oh, back to the light.
Oh, for sure.
Do they have a location?
I understand they have 40 acres.
I have to count it.
So, I'll let mine.
Yeah, but I don't know if anything else.
And I don't know what that is.
80 acres.
Well, there's only 40 out there, but the old cemetery, not old county center.
It's all on straight on the up there.
There's only 36.
Yeah, there's only 40 out there.
On old six.
Because the other 40 sets on the cemetery.
So, the only 40 they can build.
And that's outside of the city of Limit Square.
Yes.
From a context standpoint of what they have.
You've actually said, I have been involved in just that first year.
I was involved in that.
There's not been much communication for me.
Personally, so I'm not sure what the context standpoint from getting that thing off
ground.
I mean, if this is something the city is moving forward.
Is this something?
Is these use sports?
Is this something the city is going to take over?
Since they don't currently run any use sports?
I could see that.
a number of the software program, this will be year number two, right, you know, you have
to ask about that one. Unfortunately, a lot of the parents are just not stepping up these
days, so I'm not like kids not playing, so we'll step up and take over for the need to.
Well, the 40 acres the county has hasn't been any progress, so I'm supposed to call a play flow.
I honestly don't know how I can speak to them. I say about actually, I'd be more involved
in setting up a meeting with the client and before the work started, make sure it's something
that I don't think that I don't think that 40 acres still available to them if they have
anything, because I think they had a year, like progress, we're back to the county, from
my bank county commissioner. Question, how many wrong about that's worth to it?
Well, I think it'd be wise to visit the crime before trying to move forward with this and see
what they have planned out. I'm drawn out whether there's acreage, currently available, we're
not, I mean, if you're just looking for a plan, I'm not going to throw that, I'll just
not see how the 40 acres anymore. I'll just see what's out there.
There's obviously a lot of stuff, it just doesn't get too much in detail, so I'll get a little bit
more detail about it. I'm not sure what firm they used to get their plan, and he's tough to
get. So I guess we'll table this and you'll get my clothes. Yeah, I'll see you in the
office for the next time. I'll be taking the action.
I'll be taking the action. All right, we'll see you next time.
Seven of award-least purchase agreements, Q24-Destroy, to bank your grand-lake for the 2024 F-354 pickup
truck, brush truck for the fire department, give it a related signing, the payment authority
and the city matter is, does it need?
Mayor and Council, we sent out solicitations to five different lending institutions, and you
can see the order of where the rates came in and everything. Banker of grand-lake had a bid
that was $240 less than the next closest bid, which is for a national bank, and we recommend
setting up lease contract with bank of grand-lake for this truck.
All right, these trucks that we've wanted to get the author code with it. I know it's
worth, you know, of course we'll buy a lot of bid. We've wanted a lot of vehicles, and from one
on the toll, and then in what I see, they've been just pushed back further and further on many
occasions. In some cases, there are some new vehicles.
that they're purchased at now, that they didn't back, you know.
I recognize those, the city will run the trucks or cars and everything down to really there's not much value to them at all.
So, you know, they're watching their pennies for sure.
I'm like emotional proof.
Okay.
Hi.
Hey.
Lord Lee's purchase, your aim at Q24-10 to bank grant rate for a 24F-254 pickup truck.
The street department give related signing and payment authority to the city manager is the me.
On this particular one, we sent out the solicitations both at the same time and pretty much all the brands and everything except dollar amounts changed a little.
Thank you, Grandlight, pay me in the $360 dollars in $69 cents less than a first national buy the next close.
Better.
And we recommend sitting up the least contract on this one with Grandlight.
Motion to approve.
Take.
So, both.
All right.
Boydance.
He's set.
Center.
Perfect.
Bye.
Thank you.
.
The.
Thank you.
I'm on the.
To take.
To the.
Then listen to.
To.
to.
To the.
To.
I would say essentially that since that decision came down as a favorable decision for us in the city of myoma,
in our citizens, I read the headline of a article after decades of frequent flooding in my island.
Another North East Oklahoma town is a long and yo show revered.
A federal regulatory agency has determined the Grand River Dan Authority is responsible.
Now, Jardie has to have been ordered to purchase frequently flooded lands upstream for Grand Lake.
So, for decades.
of this, I know, back in 1985 was first on my flooded
Christie, lived in my same neighborhood.
I think she also got flooded at the same time.
So it's been 86, 85 was mine.
So you got this?
Well, that's what I told you about.
But I'm going all along, Conner.
So this fight has been going on for many of us
for many, many years.
So, getting this win was pretty big for my Emma.
Where it leads to, we're not 100% sure yet.
Maybe I may have some ideas on timeframes.
But we know there's more to come.
We know if I saw it over.
But whenever we've voted on stuff and had to decide stuff,
and decide whether this goes on or not,
sometimes you're like, I don't know, for, you know,
we don't just the right thing to do, but you know,
all we're doing it right.
And this proves that we work.
This proves that the fight that matters before me,
city managers before Bo, Councils before all of us,
employees before all you guys, they had the foresight
and the foretitude to keep fighting this, because it was the right thing.
And so now we get the federal agency that finally
sees the evidence and makes the right determination.
So I know my mom is not good health right now.
She's in the hospital probably won't make it much longer.
But I got to tell her, though, day, that we finally got this win.
And her response was, it was about time.
Somebody held those SOB's account.
And that's the attitude from the people who've been flooded
over and over and over and over.
And so it was a good decision for us.
Again, where it leads, we're not positive yet,
but it can't be any worse.
And one of the key things that was said in that order
was that GRDA had been in violation of their current
license for the last 26 years.
That doesn't make story.
So there are new license.
We'll hopefully have the restrictions that we all need to protect
since it's in the Maya.
So good one for Maya.
Second, what we're talking about, the coal in the United.
Wow.
What a show.
It's just a team pulled off in there.
It was a sell-up crowd.
I don't know if you guys see the pictures.
But look pretty cool.
Let's see the coal in full.
It's full.
Parking lots outside.
We're packed with cars.
So good job to dayning his team.
All the volunteers.
I know he could do that volunteers and staff.
And so great job by then.
And I look forward to meeting many more of those.
I don't know we got a list here of other events.
They're coming up to Coleman.
So I love to see our calendar.
Cool.
So I know Jayney.
I'm sure you were one of the volunteers.
We appreciate you and all the volunteers.
You put it out there.
It's a matter of one more to get in the world alone.
I don't know if you get it next time.
So, you must have anything?
Oh, I don't know the less.
So, the other night at the chamber, Gala,
I was given an award for volunteer the year
and I accepted that award that was supposed to be an individual award.
It was not an individual award.
I couldn't do what I do without all of you.
The city staff, that was your award.
I'm part of a team.
It's an individual.
I've never really been good at anything.
But as a teammate, I always win.
So, thank you guys for being my teammates.
You're being recognized for what's going on in the community.
So, it was a team award.
Thank you all.
No, that.
So, next.
Same hand recommendations.
I don't really have anything on the map.
I feel like I've been somewhat employed for the last couple of weeks.
I've been battling the COVID.
I'm thrilled to be back in the office.
And that's that.
I have that behind me.
Obviously, that's been something along with the flu that's been going around the city.
And so, it could be very disruptive this time.
Thank you.
Thanks to everybody here that kept everything going as I knew you would.
Kimby is amazing as always.
And we were in constant contact.
And we were able to do a lot of things remotely.
So, I didn't feel like I was too far behind the egg bone when I came in today.
But I'm glad to be back here in the encoder.
We're glad to have you back.
All right.
14.
This may be continued from council chambers.
Read me in the suffering of the purpose of the executive session.